My dream is to build the world's first
حلمي أن أبني أول حديقة في العالم
underground park in New York City.
تحت الأرض في مدينة نيويورك.
Now, why would someone want to build an underground park,
لكن لماذا يريد أحدنا أن يبني حديقة تحت الأرض؟
and why in New York City?
ولماذا في نيويورك تحديداً ؟
These three tough little buggers
هؤلاء الأشقياء الصغار الثلاثة
are, on the left, my grandmother, age five,
هم من اليسار، جدتي في سن الخامسة،
and then her sister and brother,
ثم أختها و أخوها
ages 11 and nine.
كانت أعمارهم حينها 11 و 9 سنوات.
This photo was taken just before they left
التقِطَت هذه الصورة قبل مغادرتهم
from Italy to immigrate to the United States,
إيطاليا للهجرة إلى الولايات المتحدة،
just about a century ago.
قبل حوالي قرن.
And like many immigrants at the time,
وكغالبية المهاجرين حينها،
they arrived on the Lower East Side
فقد وصولوا إلى الجانب الشرقي السفلي
in New York City
في مدينة نيويورك
and they encountered a crazy melting pot.
وواجهوا جنون تعدد الأعراق هناك.
What was amazing about their generation
الأمر الذي ميز جيلهم
was that they were not only building new lives
أنهم لم يكونوا يبنون حياة جديدة لهم فقط
in this new, unfamiliar area,
في هذه المنطقة الجديدة، والتي لم يعتادوا عليها،
but they were also literally building the city.
بل كانوا يبنون المدينة أيضا بكل ما في الكلمة من معنى.
I've always been fascinated by those decades
لطالما كنت مندهشا بتلك العقود
and by that history,
وبذلك التاريخ،
and I would often beg my grandmother
وكنت دائما ما أتوسل جدتي
to tell me as many stories as possible
لكي تروي لي أكبر قدر ممكن من القصص
about the old New York.
عن نيويورك القديمة.
But she would often just shrug it off,
لكنها غالبا ما كانت تتجاهلني،
tell me to eat more meatballs, more pasta,
وتطلب من أن آكل المزيد من كرات اللحم والباستا،
and so I very rarely got
لذلك فإنني نادرا ما كنت أحصل
any of the history that I wanted to hear about.
على معلومات عن التاريخ الذي كنت أريد أن أسمع عنه.
The New York City that I encountered
نيويورك التي صادفتها
felt pretty built up.
مليئة بالمباني.
I always knew as a kid that I wanted
لطالما عرفت منذ أن كنت صغيرا أنني كنت أريد
to make a difference, and to somehow
أن أصنع الفرق،وبطريقة ما
make the world more beautiful, more interesting
أن أجعل العالم أكثر جمالا وإثارة للاهتمام
and more just.
وأكثر عدالة.
I just didn't really know how.
لكنني لم أكن أعرف يمكنني القيام بذلك.
At first, I thought I wanted to go work abroad,
في البداية كنت أريد أن أعمل بالخارج،
so I took a job with UNICEF in Kenya.
لذلك قبلت بوظيفة مع اليونيسيف في كينيا.
But it felt weird to me that I knew more about
لكنني الأمر كان غريبا بالنسبة لي أن أعرف أكثر
local Kenyan politics than the politics of my own hometown.
عن السياسة الكينية المحلية أكثر من معرفتي بسياسة بلدي.
I took a job with the City of New York,
حصلت على عمل مع إدارة مدينة نيويورك،
but very quickly felt frustrated
لكنني سرعان ما أحسست بالإحباط
with the slowness of government bureaucracy.
بسبب بطء بيروقراطية الحكومة.
I even took a job at Google,
حتى أنني حصلت على عمل في غوغل،
where very fast I drank the Kool-Aid
حيث تشربت بسرعة أفكارهم دون جدال
and believed almost wholeheartedly
وآمنت بكل قلبي
that technology could solve all social problems.
أنه يمكن للتكنولوجيا أن تحل كل المشاكل الاجتماعية.
But I still didn't feel like I was making the world a better place.
لكنني كنت لاأزال أشعر أنني لم أغير العالم للأفضل.
It was in 2009 that my friend
سنة 2009،نبهني صديقي
and now business partner James Ramsey
والذي هو شريكي الآن في العمل جيمس رامزي
alerted me to the location of a pretty spectacular site,
إلى وجود موقع جميل ذي منظر رائع،
which is this.
إلى هذا المكان.
This is the former trolley terminal
هذه هي محطة العربات السابقة
that was the depot for passengers
والذي كانت محطة للركاب
traveling over the Williamsburg Bridge
المسافرين حول جسر ويليامسبيرغ
from Brooklyn to Manhattan,
من بروكلين إلى مانهاتن،
and it was open between 1908 and 1948,
والتي كانت تعمل في الفترة بين 1908 و 1948،
just around the time when my grandparents were
حوالي الحقبة التي كان أجدادي
living right in the area.
يعيشون فيها في هذه المنطقة.
And we learned also that the site
وعلمنا أيضا أن هذا الموقع
was entirely abandoned in 1948.
كان قد أُخلي تماما سنة 1948.
Fascinated by this discovery,
وباندهاش كبير بهذا الاكتشاف،
we begged the authorities to draw us into the space,
توسلنا إلى السلطات بأن يسمحوا لنا بالدخول إلى ذلك الفضاء،
and we finally got a tour,
وأخيرا حصلنا على جولة هناك؛
and this is what we saw.
وكان هذا ماشاهدناه.
Now, this photo doesn't really do it justice.
في الحقيقة هذه الصورة ليست منصفة تماما.
It's kind of hard to imagine the unbelievably magical
إذ من الصعب تخيل الإحساس الساحر
feeling that you have when you get in this space.
الذي سيغمرك عندما تدخل هذا الفضاء.
It's a football field of unused land
إنها أرض متخلى عنها بمساحة ملعب كرة قدم
immediately below a very crowded area of the city,
تقع مباشرة تحت منطقة مزدحمة من المدينة،
and it almost feels like you're Indiana Jones
ستشعر تقريبا وكأنك إنديانا جونز
on an archaeological dig,
في مهمة حفر أثري،
and all the details are all still there.
وأن كل التفاصيل لم تبرح مكانها.
It's really pretty remarkable.
إنه أمر استثنائي فعلا.
Now, the site itself is located at the very heart
الآن، يقع هذا الموقع تماما في قلب
of the Lower East Side,
الجهة السفلى الشرقية،
and today it still remains one of the most
والتي لا تزال اليوم واحدة من أكثر
crowded neighborhoods in the city.
الأحياء ازدحاما في المدينة.
New York City has two thirds the green space
لدى مدينة نيويورك ثلثا المساحات الخضراء
per resident as other big cities,
لكل مواطن،كما في المدن الكبرى الأخرى،
and this neighborhood as one tenth the green space.
ويوجد في هذا الحي مايعادل عشر المساحات الخضراء.
So we immediately started thinking about how we
لذلك بدأنا فورا في التفكير في كيفية
could take this site and turn it into something
تحويل هذا الموقع إلى مكان
that could be used for the public,
يستطيع العامة الاستفادة منه،
but also could potentially even be green.
وكذلك من المحتمل حتى أن يكون صديقا للبيئة.
Our plan, in a nutshell,
خطتنا،باختصار،
is to draw natural sunlight underground
أن نجذب ضوء الشمس الطبيعي إلى ماتحت الأرض
using a simple system that harvests sunlight above the street,
باستعمال نظام بسيط يجمع ضوء الشمس في أعلى الشارع،
directs it below the city sidewalks,
وتوجيهه تحت أرصفة المدينة،
and would allow plants and trees to grow
مما سيسمح للنباتات والأشجار بالنمو
with the light that's directed underneath.
بالضوء الذي سيوجّه تحت الأرض.
With this approach, you could take a site
وباتباع هذه المقاربة،يمكنك أن تأخذ موقعا
that looks like this today
والذي يبدو على هذا النحو
and transform it into something
وتحوله إلى مكان
that looks like this.
يبدو على هذه الشاكلة.
In 2011, we first released some of these images,
سنة 2011،بدأنا بنشر بعض من هذه الصور،
and what was funny was,
وماكان طريفا في الأمر،
a lot of people said to us, "Oh, it kind of looks
أن كثيرا من الناس قالوا لنا:"أوه، إنها تبدو
like the High Line underground."
وكأنها حديقة "هاي لاين" لكن تحت الأرض"
And so what our nickname ended up becoming,
وهكذا انتهى بنا المطاف بتسمية مشروعنا
and what ended up sticking,
وكانت التسمية التي التصقت بالمشروع في النهاية
was the Lowline, so the Lowline was born.
هي ""ذ لو لاين"،و هكذا ولد "ذ لو لاين".
What was also clear was that people really wanted
وما كان واضحا أيضا هو رغبة الناس الشديدة
to know a lot more about how the technology
لمعرفة المزيد عما سيكون عليه
would look and feel,
شكل ومظهر التكنولوجيا،
and that there was really much more interest in this
وكان أيضا هنالك اهتمام أكبر بكثير
than we had ever thought possible.
مما كنا نتخيل حدوثه قط.
So, like a crazy person, I decided to quit my job
وبما أني شخص مجنون، قررت أن أستقيل عن عملي
and focus entirely on this project.
وأركز بشكل كامل على هذا المشروع.
Here is us with our team
هنا صورتنا مع فريقنا
putting together a technology demonstration
نضع تصوراً للتكنولوجيا
in a warehouse.
في مستودع.
Here's the underbelly of this solar canopy
وهذه هي القبة الشمسية من الداخل
which we built to show the technology.
والتي بنيناها لنعرض التكنولوجيا
You can see the six solar collectors at the center there.
يمكنكم مشاهدة ستة جامعات ضوئية في الوسط .
And here's the full exhibit all put together
وهذا شكل المعرض كاملاً بعد جمعه
in this warehouse.
في هذا المستودع.
You can see the solar canopy overhead,
يمكنك مشاهدة القبة الشمسية في الأعلى
the light streaming in,
والضوء يتدفق للداخل ،
and this entirely live green space below.
وهذه المساحة الخضراء الحية بمجملها في الأسفل.
So in the course of just a few weeks,
وفي غضون بضعة أسابيع فقط،
tens of thousands of people came to see our exhibit,
جاء عشرات الآلاف من الناس لزيارة معرضنا،
and since that time, we've grown
ومنذ ذلك الحين،بدأت تزداد
our numbers of supporters both locally
أعداد مؤيدينا في الداخل
and among design enthusiasts all over the world.
وبين صفوف الشغوفين بالتصميم حول العالم بأسره.
Here's a rendering of the neighborhood
هذه صور عن تصورنا للحي
just immediately above the Line's site,
والذي يقع تماما أعلى موقع " لاين"،
and a rendering of how it will look
وتصورنا عن كيف سيبدو
after major redevelopment that is coming
بعد التحديثات الكبيرة المتوقعة
over the course of the next 10 years.
في غضون العشر سنوات المقبلة.
Notice how crowded the neighborhood still feels
لاحظوا الازدحام الذي لا يزال يبدو الحي عليه
and how there's really a lack of green space.
وكيف أنه يفتقر فعلا للمساحات الخضراء.
So what we're proposing is really something that will
لذلك فما نعرضه هو فعلا شيء
add one football field of green space
سيضيف فضاء أخضرا بمساحة ملعب كرة قدم
underneath this neighborhood, but more importantly
تحت هذ الحي، ولكن الأهم هو
will introduce a really community-driven focus
أنه سيقدم فعلا مشروعا يركز على اعتبارات المجتمع المحلي،
in a rapidly gentrifying area.
في هذه المنطقة سريعة التغير.
And right now, we're focusing very closely
وحالياً ، نحن نركز عن قرب على
on how we engage with the City of New York
كيفية شراكتنا مع إدارة مدينة نيويورك
on really transforming the overall ecosystem
لتحويل النظام البيئي بأكمله
in an integrated way.
بشكل متكامل.
Here's our rendering of how we would actually
وهذا تصورنا عن كيفية
invite people into the space itself.
دعوة الناس إلى هذا الفضاء في حد ذاته.
So here you see this iconic entrance
وهذا هو المدخل الابداعي
in which we would literally peel up the street
والذي يظهر كيف أننا حرفيا ننزع القشرة عن الشارع
and reveal the historical layers of the city,
لكشف هذه الطبقات التاريخية من للمدينة،
and invite people into this warm underground space.
ودعوة الناس إلى هذا المكان الدافئ تحت الأرض.
In the middle of winter, when it's absolutely freezing outside,
في منتصف الشتاء،وحين تشتد البرودة في الخارج،
the last place you'd want to go would be
آخر مكان تفكر في الذهاب إليه
an outdoor space or outdoor park.
فضاء أو حديقة في الخارج.
The Lowline would really be a four-season space
سيكون"ذ لو لاين" فضاء مناسبا للفصول الأربعة
and a respite for the city.
ومتنفسا للمدينة.
So I like to think that the Lowline actually brings
ويعجبني أن أفكر أن "ذ لو لاين" يكمل
my own family's story full circle.
حلقة قصة عائلتي.
If my grandparents and my parents were really
إذا كان أجدادي و آبائي حقا
focused on building the city up and out,
قد ركزواعلى بناء المدينة من الداخل و الخارج،
I think my generation is focused on reclaiming
فإنني أعتقد أن جيلي يركز على استعادة
the spaces that we already have,
هذه المساحات التي كنا نملك مسبقا،
rediscovering our shared history,
وإعادة اكتشاف تاريخنا المشترك ،
and reimagining how we can make our communities
ونتخيل مرة أخرى كيف يمكن أن نجعل مجتمعاتنا المحلية
more interesting, more beautiful and more just.
مثيرة للاهتمام أكثر،جميلة أكثر و منصفة أكثر.
Thanks.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)